<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Moyan&#39;s Website on Moyan&#39;s Website</title>
    <link>https://mmy12580.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Moyan&#39;s Website on Moyan&#39;s Website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Posts</title>
      <link>https://mmy12580.github.io/posts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mmy12580.github.io/posts/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://mmy12580.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mmy12580.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;about-me&#34;&gt;About Me&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am now working as Principal Scientist for &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.course5i.com&#34;&gt;Course5i AI Lab&lt;/a&gt;, Toronto. My main focus is to build scalable and transferable B2B AI products and services to more than 20 countries and regions, e.g., Microsoft, Lenovo, Colgate Palmolive, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My &lt;strong&gt;main interest&lt;/strong&gt; is to build an &amp;ldquo;end-to-end&amp;rdquo; human-computer interaction system given kinds of &amp;ldquo;knowledge&amp;rdquo;, including transfer learning, MTL, meta-learning, and self-supervised learning etc.  If you are interested in my experience or the website, have a look at my &lt;a href=&#34;https://mmy12580.github.io/resume/moyan_resume.pdf&#34;&gt;resume&lt;/a&gt; for more information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-the-blog&#34;&gt;Why the blog?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I created this blog not only to help me refresh my memory about engineering details, theory behind models, training tricks, and optimization techniques, but also to communicate with people who read and share what they know or think, so we can expand our own &amp;ldquo;knowledge&amp;rdquo; base togeter. Feel free to reach me out from any accessible source, e.g., email or wechat, at my &lt;a href=&#34;https://moyan.ml&#34;&gt;homepage&lt;/a&gt;. I am looking forward to any interesting topic discussions or feedbacks. Thanks😄.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;just-for-fun&#34;&gt;Just for fun&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Click the &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; on the top left of the web page to switch the theme of the website.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>