<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>machine learning on Moyan&#39;s Website</title>
    <link>https://mmy12580.github.io/tags/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in machine learning on Moyan&#39;s Website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mmy12580.github.io/tags/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Normalization in Deep Learning</title>
      <link>https://mmy12580.github.io/posts/normalization_for_dl/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mmy12580.github.io/posts/normalization_for_dl/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Batch Normalization (BN) has been treated as one of the standard &amp;ldquo;plug-in&amp;rdquo; tool to deep neural networks since its first release. It is been proved to be very helpful in a tons of machine learning applications due to its several advantages as followings:
 faster training higher learning rate easier initialization more activations support deeper but simpler architecture regularization  Algorithms:
Here, $\gamma$ and $\beta$ are the parameters to be learned, the parameters update is based on chain rule like followings:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A quick summary for imbalanced data</title>
      <link>https://mmy12580.github.io/posts/imbalanced_learn_summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2019 11:28:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mmy12580.github.io/posts/imbalanced_learn_summary/</guid>
      <description>Data imbalance occurs when the sample size in the data classes are unevenly distributed. Such situation is encountered in many applications in industry. Sometimes, it could be extremely imbalanced e.g click-through rate prediction, fraud detection, or cancer diagnosis etc. Most of machine learning techniques work well with balanced training data but they face challenges when the dataset classes are imbalanced. In such situation, classification methods tend to be biased towards the majority class.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>